A Finding Aid to the Janet deCoux Papers, 1895-2000, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Janet deCoux papers
1895-2000
Archives of American Art
De Coux, Janet, 1904-1999
AAA.decojane
Archival Resource Key
3.92 Linear feet
The papers of sculptor Janet DeCoux date from 1895-2000 and measure 3.92 linear feet. The collection documents DeCoux's career through scattered biographical material, correspondence, audio cassette tapes of an autobiographical narrative, an interview transcript, miscellaneous notes and writings, sketchbooks and drawings, files for commissioned sculpture projects, printed material, photographs of DeCoux, family members, friends, colleagues, and artwork.
Provenance
The Janet deCoux papers were donated in 1992 by the artist and in two later installments in 2000-2001 by her longtime companion, Eliza Miller.
Related Material
Also found in the Archives of American Art is an oral history interview with Janet deCoux done by George Gurney, May 5, 1978.
Alternative Forms Available
Portions of this collection are available on 35mm microfilm reel 4909 at Archives of American Art offices and through interlibrary loan. Researchers should note that the arrangement of the material described in the container inventory does not reflect the arrangement of the collection on microfilm.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. Use requires an appointment.
Biographical Note
Janet deCoux was born on October 5, 1904 in Niles, Michigan, the youngest of the five children of Bertha Wright deCoux and Rev. Charles John deCoux, an Episcopal clergyman. The family moved to Grand Rapids in 1908 and four years later to a farm in Gibsonia, outside Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.
deCoux studied with Joseph Bailey Ellis at the Carnegie Institute of Technology from 1925 to 1927. She then apprenticed in the New York studio of C. Paul Jennewein for fifteen months, followed by a year at the Gorham Bronze Division learning architectural modeling. She also worked with Aristide Cianfarani in Providence, and for Alvin Meyer in Chicago. While serving her apprenticeships, she attended night school at the New York School of Industrial Arts, the Rhode Island School of Design, and the Art Institute of Chicago. deCoux was then employed in James Earle Fraser's studio where she had previously assisted Gozo Kawamura.
In 1932 deCoux met Eliza Miller in the sculpture department of Carnegie Tech, beginning a sixty-year relationship in which they shared a shop and adjoining studios in Gibsonia, Pennsylvania. For several months in 1935, deCoux traveled to Germany, Italy, and Switzerland, where she joined her friend Aly Moore, the wife of sculptor Bruce Moore. She first met longtime friend Father Hughson on a ship returning to the United States from Europe.
A Guggenheim Fellowship awarded to deCoux in 1938 was renewed for a second year. In 1943, she became resident instructor at Cranbrook Academy of Art.
Janet deCoux died in December 1999.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of sculptor Janet deCoux measure 3.92 linear feet and date from 1895 to 2000. Found within the papers are scattered biographical material, including curriculum vitae and a file concerning deCoux's induction as a Distinguished Daughter of Pennsylvania. Correspondence is primarily between family, friends, and colleagues. It includes letters from Carl Milles, Bruce Moore, C.P. Jennewein, the Guild of Liturgy, Art and Design (GLAD), the Liturgical Arts Society, Inc., sculptor James Earle Fraser, offering advice on various sculpture projects, his wife Laura Gardin Fraser, a letter of congratulations from Paul Manship on the occasion of deCoux's election to the National Academy of Design, and approximately fifty letters, 1944-1952, from Anne Morrow Lindbergh, writer and wife of aviator Charles Lindbergh. There are also one or two letters from Lu Duble, Joseph Bailey Ellis, Mark Tobey, and Albert Wein.
Found within the papers are a transcript of an interview of deCoux by George Gurney, and audio cassettes with transcripts of an autobiographical narrative by deCoux. Miscellaneous notes and writings include autobiographical accounts and poems by deCoux and miscellaneous writings by others. Seven of deCoux's sketchbooks and a folder of drawings by deCoux, as well as a portrait of deCoux by C. Paul Jennewein are found in the Artwork series. Project files contain letters, receipts, clippings, brochures, and photographs for sculpture projects primarily commissioned by religious organizations. Printed material includes clippings, exhibition catalogs, and miscellaneous brochures. Photographs are of deCoux, family members, friends including Anne Morrow Lindbergh and her children, colleagues including James Earle Fraser, Laura Gardin Fraser, Carl Milles, and Bruce Moore, and sculpture.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 8 series. Glass plate negative housed separately and closed to researchers.
Missing Title
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1895-1993 (Box 1; 13 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1895-2000 (Boxes 1-2; 1.0 linear feet)
Series 3: Interviews, 1978, 1990 (Box 2; 3 folders)
Series 4: Notes and Writings, 1937-1996 (Box 2; 23 folders)
Series 5: Artwork, 1928-1929 (Boxes 2, 6; 9 folders)
Series 6: Project Files, 1942-1982 (Boxes 2-3, 6; 36 folders)
Series 7: Printed Material, 1906-2000 (Box 3; 20 folders)
Series 8: Photographs, 1926-1996 (Boxes 3-6, MGP 1; 1.3 linear feet)
Sculptors -- Pennsylvania -- Philadelphia; Educators -- Michigan; Women artists; Women sculptors; Women educators; Photographs; Sketchbooks; Drawings; Poetry; Interviews; Sound recordings; Fraser, Laura Gardin, 1889-1966; Guild of Liturgy, Art and Design; Fraser, James Earle, 1876-1953; Lindbergh, Anne Morrow, 1906-2001; Gurney, George; Liturgical Arts Society; Jennewein, Carl Paul, 1890-; Milles, Carl, 1875-1955; Manship, Paul, 1885-1966; Moore, Bruce, 1905-1980
- Biographical Material, 1895-1993; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; (Box 1; 13 folders)
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical material includes curriculum vitae, report cards, and passports. A file for the Distinguished Daughter of Pennsylvania Medal contains letters, a transcript of the ceremony, programs, directories, and photographs of the ceremony and other recipients including actress Grace Kelly. Miscellaneous family material includes a funeral card for deCoux's aunt Minnie, miscellaneous genealogical notes, and locks of deCoux's hair and her mother's hair.
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1944-1993; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Report Cards, 1926; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Passports, 1935-1984; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
  - Award Certificates, 1954-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - File for Distinguished Daughter of Pennsylvania Medal, 1954-1955; Archival Resource Key; (5 folders) (Box 1, Folder 7-11)
  - Miscellaneous Biographical Material, 1895-1969, undated; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
- Correspondence, 1895-2000; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; (Boxes 1-2; 1.0 linear feet)
  Correspondence is primarily between deCoux and family members, friends including Anne Morrow Lindbergh, and colleagues including Abastenia St. Leger Eberle, James Earle Fraser, Laura Gardin Fraser, Camille Grapin, Carl Milles, and Bruce Moore. There are one or two letters each from Lu Duble, Joseph Bailey Ellis, Mark Tobey, and Albert Wein.
  Eleven letters from James Earle Fraser, two letters from Laura Gardin Fraser, and one letter from Paul Manship have been microfilmed on reel 4909, and are arranged together in one folder.
  - Eleven Letters from James Earle Fraser, Laura Gardin Fraser, and Paul Manship, 1935-1946; Archival Resource Key; (see also reel 4909) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, undated; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 15-17)
  - Correspondence, 1895-1919; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1927; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1928; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1929; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 21-23)
  - Correspondence, 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1931; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 25-26)
  - Correspondence, 1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, 1934; Archival Resource Key; (5 folders) (Box 1, Folder 29-33)
  - Correspondence, 1935; Archival Resource Key; (6 folders) (Box 1, Folder 34-39)
  - Correspondence, 1936; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 40-41)
  - Correspondence, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence, 1938; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 43-44)
  - Correspondence, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence, 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence, 1944; Archival Resource Key; (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 49-52)
  - Correspondence, 1945; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 53-54)
  - Correspondence, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Correspondence, 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Correspondence, 1948-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Correspondence, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence, 1951-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Correspondence, 1953-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Correspondence, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Correspondence, 1962; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 62-64)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Correspondence, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Correspondence, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Correspondence, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Correspondence, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Correspondence, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Correspondence, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Correspondence, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Correspondence, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1992-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Interviews, 1978, 1990; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; (Box 2; 3 folders)
  This series consists of a transcript of an interview of deCoux conducted by George Gurney on May 5, 1978, and audiocassettes with transcripts of an autobiographical narrative by deCoux.
  - Transcript of Interview of Janet deCoux by George Gurney, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Audiocassettes of Autobiographical Narrative by deCoux, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Transcript of Autobiographical Narrative by deCoux, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Notes and Writings, 1937-1996; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; (Box 2; 23 folders)
  This series includes miscellaneous notes and writings including autobiographical accounts and poems by deCoux. Miscellaneous writings by others include poems and a prayer written by deCoux's father, Charles J. deCoux.
  - Lists of Artwork, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Pages from Exhibition Guest Book, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Autobiographical Writings by Janet deCoux, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Poems by deCoux, 1937-1938, undated; Archival Resource Key; (8 folders) (Box 2, Folder 17-24)
  - Notebook of Poems by deCoux, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Book Reviews by deCoux, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous Writings by deCoux, 1937-1991, undated; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 27-29)
  - Poems by Charles J. deCoux, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Prayer by Charles J. deCoux, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Autobiographical Typescript by Bertha Wright deCoux, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Typescript "Beloved and Lovely" by Charles P. Price, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Typescript "The Liberal Tradition of the Gospel" by Charles P. Price, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous Writings by Others, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Artwork, 1928-1929; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; (Boxes 2, 6; 9 folders)
  Artwork consists of sketchbooks and drawings including a pencil portrait of deCoux by C. Paul Jennewein.
  - Sketchbook 1, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Sketchbook 2, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Sketchbook 3, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Sketchbook 4, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Sketchbook 5, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Sketchbook 6, 1928; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Sketchbook 7, 1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Miscellaneous Drawings, 1928, undated; Archival Resource Key; (see also Box 6) (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Oversized Pencil Portrait of Janet deCoux by C. Paul Jennewein, 1928; Archival Resource Key (Box 6)
- Project Files, 1942-1982; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; (Boxes 2-3, 6; 36 folders)
  Project files contain letters, receipts, clippings, brochures, and photographs concerning sculpture projects primarily commissioned by religious organizations.
  - Bas-Relief for Post Office, Girard, Pennsylvania, 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Statue of the Madonna, St. Mary Roman Catholic Church, Manhasset, New York, 1943-1946; Archival Resource Key; (4 folders; see also Box 6) (Box 2, Folder 45-48)
  - Statue of St. Benedict, St. Vincent Archabbey, Latrobe, Pennsylvania, 1947-1949; Archival Resource Key; (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 49-52)
  - "Luce Doors," St. Ann Chapel, Palo Alto, California, 1952; Archival Resource Key; (see also Box 6) (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Statue of the Madonna, Roman Catholic Church, Fishers Island, New York, 1955-1958; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 54-55)
  - Altar, Crucifix, and Pyx for Order of St. Helena, Vails Gate, New York, 1959-1962; Archival Resource Key; (8 folders) (Box 2, Folder 56-63)
  - Statue of William Penn, William Penn Memorial Museum, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania, 1962-1970; Archival Resource Key; (7 folders) (Box 2, Folder 64-70)
  - Altar, Baptismal Font, and Crucifix, St. Stephen and Incarnation Episcopal Church, Washington, D.C., 1964-1967; Archival Resource Key; (4 folders) (Box 3, Folder 1-4)
  - Statue of St. Stephen, St. Stephen Episcopal Church, Sweickley, Pennsylvania, 1968-1970; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
  - Bell Tower, Convent of St. Helena, Vails Gate, New York, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Two Oversized Photographs of Statue of the Madonna, St. Mary Roman Catholic Church, Manhasset, New York, 1943-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 6)
  - Two Oversized Reproductions of Elevation Drawings, St. Ann Chapel, Palo Alto, California, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 6)
- Printed Material, 1906-2000; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; (Box 3; 20 folders)
  Printed material includes clippings, exhibition catalogs, reproductions of artwork, programs, a passenger list from deCoux's European trip, a high school yearbook, and miscellaneous brochures.
  - Clippings, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, 1906-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, 1952-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, 1971-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, 1980-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, 1990-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Clippings, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1944-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Reproductions of Artwork by deCoux, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Reproductions of Artwork by Others, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Programs, 1911-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Passenger List from the S. S. Washington, 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Booklet of Transcript of Informal Talk by Carl Milles, 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Book, The Poetry and Drawings by Janet deCoux, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - High School Yearbook, 1921; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Brochures, 1956-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Photographs, 1926-1996; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; (Boxes 3-6, MGP 1; 1.3 linear feet)
  Photographs are of deCoux, family members, friends including Anne Morrow Lindbergh and her children, colleagues including James Earle Fraser, Laura Gardin Fraser, Henry Kreis, Carl Milles, Bruce Moore, and students at Cranbrook Academy of Art, residences, deCoux's studio, and of an exhibition at the Carnegie Institute. Photographs are also of artwork for which project files were not created.
  Existence and Location of Copies
  Glass plate negatives have been digitized.
  - Photographs of Janet deCoux, 1926-1996, undated; Archival Resource Key; (5 folders) (Box 3, Folder 28-32)
  - Photographs of Family Members, undated; Archival Resource Key; (see also Box 6) (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Photographs of Family Grave Sites, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Photographs of James Earle Fraser, Fraser's Studio, Laura Gardin Fraser, Bruce Moore, and Henry Kreis, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Photographs of Anne Morrow Lindbergh and Children, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Photographs of Carl Milles, 1943, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Photographs of Miscellaneous Friends and Colleagues, 1943-1963, undated; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 38-39)
  - Photographs of Residences, 1953, undated; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 40-42)
  - Photographs of Studio, 1947, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Photographs of Exhibition at Carnegie Institute, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Photographs of Bust Aaron, undated; Archival Resource Key; (see also Box 6) (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Photographs of Altar, Methodist Church, Brooklyn, Pennsylvania, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Photographs of Aumbry, Christ Church, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Christ and St. Paul, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Christ in the Garden, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Photographs of Busts Boy and Girl, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Photographs of Statue Conversion of St. Paul, undated; Archival Resource Key; (see also Box 6) (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Photographs of Aluminum Crucifix, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Photographs of Cherrywood Crucifix, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Dancers, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Deposition of Christ, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Doubting Thomas, undated; Archival Resource Key; (see also Box 6) (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Photograph of Sculpture Eve, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Photographs of Model for a Fountain, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 58)
    Scope and Contents
    (1 glass plate negatives housed in MGP 1)
  - Photographs of Sculpture for the Hamm Memorial, undated; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 59-60)
  - Photographs of Relief Sculpture Jacob's Dream, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Jesus and St. John, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Photographs of Bust John Lindsay, undated; Archival Resource Key; (see also Box 6) (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Judas, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Madonna and Child, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Mother Earth, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Mother Seton, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Photograph of Relief Sculpture The Poet, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Photographs of Incised Drawing on Slate Prodigal Son, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Prophet, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Photographs of Relief Sculpture Resurrection, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Ruth and Naomi, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Photographs of Relief Sculpture St. David and St. Paul, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Photographs of Sanford Table, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Photographs of Relief Portrait Sarah Campbell deCoux, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Photographs of Relief Sculptures The Swimmers or Night and Day, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Woman Touching Christ's Garment, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Photographs of Sculpture John the Baptist, 1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Savanarola, 1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Deborah's Song, 1938; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders; see also Box 6) (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
  - Photographs of Relief Sculpture St. Angela and the Young Girl for the College of New Rochelle, New York, 1938; Archival Resource Key; (see also Box 6) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Photographs of Relief Sculpture for the Food Building, New York World??s Fair, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Photographs of Medal Thou Sluggard, 1942-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Photographs of Relief Portrait Elizabeth Morrow, 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 8)